SUNGHEE YUN

 $sunghee.yun@gmail.com\\ +1-408-549-4077$

Profile

I am Co-founder & CAIO of AI Technology and Product Strategy @ Erudio Bio, Inc. with expertise in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Product and Technology Strategy. I have led AI and optimization projects in the fields such as semiconductor design / manufacturing / testing, strategic marketing and sales, e-commerce, industrial AI, and AI-enhanced biotech based on my fundamental understanding of the inner workings of and insight into AI with knowledge on convex optimization underpinning all AI algorithms.

My strength lies in applying core AI technologies such as large language model (LLM) and generative AI (genAI) for development and productionization of a number of software and services to many customers for B2B and B2C business. I am also consulted for state and government policy-making with topics such as potential changes of labor market driven by of AI technology, ethical, social and political issues on AI, and supply chain and manufacturing of AI semiconductor chips including CPU, GPU, and AI accelerators.

Before joining Erudio Bio, Inc., I co-founded Gauss Labs Inc., an industrial AI start-up company, as CTO & Head of Global R&D. I led many high-profile AI projects at Amazon increasing revenue by 200 million USD via Amazon Mobile Shopping App. Prior to Amazon, I worked for Samsung Electronics leading AI and optimization projects for semiconductor design, manufacturing, and testing.

WORK AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Co-founder & CAIO - AI Technology & Product Strategy, Erudio Bio, Inc. Dec-2023 - Present

 AI Technology, and Product Strategy to develop and productionize AI-enhanced multiplomic multiplexing bio data platform

Adjunct Professor, Electronic Engineering Department, Sogang UniversityMar-2020 – PresentAdvisory Professor, Information and Communication Engineering, DGISTFeb-2020 – Present

• Consultation on academic direction, industry trend in Silicon Valley, social scientific / ethical / legal issues of AI & special lectures and seminars

Network Expert, Gerson Lehrman Gruop (GLG), New York City, U.S.A. Feb-2022 – Present

• Help clients solve their toughest business and technical challenges around manufacturing profit and sales improvement, e-commerce customer engagement level improvement, and AI technology in biotech industry

Co-founder & CTO - Senior Fellow, Gauss Labs Inc., Palo Alto, CA. U.S.A

Way-2000 - Nov-2023

VP - Fellow, SK hynix

Sep-2020 - Jun-2021

• Business, Product & Tech Development / Operate US Headquarters

Senior Applied Scientist, Amazon.com, Inc., Vancouver, BC, Canada Nov-2018 – Aug-2020

- AI for Mobile Shopping App Main Menu Personalization system creating revenue by 200MM USD
- TestBot AI agents patching and updating software test scenarios

Principal Engineer, Software R&D Center, Samsung Electronics

Dec-2016 – Jun-2017

• Decentralized Federated AI for Internet of Things (IoT)

Principal Engineer, Strategic Sales & Marketing Team, Samsung Electronics Dec-2015 – Dec-2016

• AI for Sales Forecasting of world-wide NAND Flash and DRAM markets

Principal Engineer, Design Technology Team, Samsung Electronics Mar-2012 – Nov-2015

- AI for Optimal Scheduling System for Test & Package Factories in Suzhou, China,
- \bullet Generic AI & Optimization Platform for automatization of semiconductor design & manufacturing

Senior Engineer, CAE Team, Semiconductor R&D Center, Samsung Electronics Dec-2004 – Feb-2012

- NAND Flash Memory Core Operation Optimization achieving 10% accuracy improvement
- Generic Digital/Analog/Mixed-signal Circuit Optimization
- High density DRAM failure rate estimation achieving > 100X prediction time reduction

Research Assistant, EE Department, Stanford University, CA, U.S.A.

Mar-1999 - Nov-2004

• Multi-objective Logic Circuits Design using Convex Optimization

Development Engineer, Voyan Technology, Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

Sep-2000 - Aug-2001

• Digital Subscriber Line (DSL) Diagnosis & Length Adjustable Transmission Line Emulator

EDUCATION

| Ph.D., Electrical Engineering - Advisor: Prof. Stephen Boyd | Sep-2001 - Nov-2004 |
|---|---------------------|
| Stanford University, CA, U.S.A. | |
| M.S., Electrical Engineering - Advisor: Prof. Stephen Boyd | Sep-1998 - Jun-2000 |
| Stanford University, CA, U.S.A. | |
| B.S., Electrical Engineering - Magna Cum Laude | Mar-1994 - Feb-1998 |
| Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea | |
| Honors and Awards | |
| • Best Invention Award at Amazon.com, Inc. | 2019 |
| • Best Paper Award at Samsung Semiconductor Technical Paper Award | 2011 |
| • Best Paper Award at Samsung Group Best Paper Award | 2005 |
| • Best Paper Award at International Symposium on Quality Electronic Design (ISQ | ED) 2005 |
| • Full Scholarship from Samsung Electronics | 2001 - 2004 |
| • Samsung Frontier Membership | 1999 |
| • Ranked 2nd in the Ph.D. Qualifying Examination, Stanford University | 1999 |
| • Full Scholarship from Korean Foundation for Advanced Study (KFAS) | 1998-2000 |
| • Graduated with Honors - Magna Cum Laude, Seoul National University (SNU) | 1998 |
| • Full Scholarship from Seoul National University (SNU) | 1994-1998 |
| • Ranked 2nd in University Entrance Examination, Seoul National University (SNU | 1994 |
| • Graduated with Honors - Summa Cum Laude, Seoul Science High School | 1993 |
| • Bronze Medal at Asian Pacific Mathematical Olympiad (APMO) | 1992 |
| • Silver Medal at Korea Mathematical Olympiad (KMO) | 1992 |

INVITED SEMINARS AND LECTURES

- "SAIT AIRC Seminar: LLM & getnAI Technology, Business, and AI Markets" invited by Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology (SAIT)
- "DGIST Seminar: LLM & getnAI Technology, Business, and AI Markets" invited by EE Department of Daegu Gyeongbuk Institute of Science and Technology (DGIST) 2024
- "Cryptography Seminar: Industrial AI Technology in Manufacturing" SNU Math Department 2024
- "SNU Data Science (DS) Seminar: Industrial AI Technology" SNU DS Graduate School 2023

| • "EE/CS Seminar: Manufacturing AI Problems and Solutions" invited by SNU | 2022 |
|--|--------------------|
| • "BK4 Seminar: Manufacturing AI Problems and Solutions" invited by Sogang University | 2022 |
| • "Time-series Machine Learning in Manufacturing" invited by Postech | 2022 |
| • "Time-series Learning and Software Platform for Manufacturing AI" invited by DGIST | 2022 |
| • "AI Frontier Summit: AI in Manufacturing and Industry Areas" invited by KICS | 2021 |
| • "Special Lecture: Electrical Engineer in the age of AI" invited by Sogang University | 2021 |
| • "Future Creation Seminar: The Future of AI" invited by Amore Pacific | 2020 |
| • "Reinforcement Learning and its Applications" invited by School of Business of UBC | 2018 |
| • "Convex Optimization for Machine Learning (ML)" invited by SNU | 2018 |
| • "Convex Optimization for Artificial Intelligence (AI)" invited by Amazon ML Meetings | 2018 |
| • "KCC Tutorial: Convex Optimization for Decentralized Machine Learning" invited by KCC 20 | 2017 |
| • "Convex Optimization for Machine Learning" invited by Samsung DRAM Development Lab | 2017 |
| \bullet "Introduction to Convex Optimization and its Applications" invited by Kyung Hee University | 2013 |
| • "Convex Optimization and its Applications" invited by SNU | 2008 |
| • "Circuit Design via Geometric Programming" invited by SNU | 2005 |
| \bullet "Convex Optimization and its Application in Circuit Design" invited by Samsung Electronics | 2002 |
| Patents | |
| • Systems and Methods for Process Monitoring and Control | 2023 |
| • Testbot AI agent: automatic software test scenario patch and modification system | 2020 |
| • Method of testing semiconductor memory device, test device, and computer readable recording for recording test program for semiconductor memory device | g medium 2017 |
| • Method and system for designing 3D semiconductor package | 2014 |
| • Methodology for estimating statistical distribution characteristics of physical parameters of semi device | iconductor 2009 |
| • Methodology for estimating statistical distribution characteristics of product parameters | 2007 |
| \bullet Length adjustable transmission line emulators with simple RLC circuits | 2001 |
| Teaching Experience | |
| Amazon Lecturer Machine Learning University, Amazon | 2018-2020 |
| • AI Mathematical Fundamentals, AI Data Science, Advanced Machine Learning Courses | |
| Samsung Electronics Lecturer Samsung Electronics | 2005-2017 |
| • Convex Optimization for AI, Machine Learning & AI | |
| • Numerical Linear Algebra for ML, Advanced Statistics | |
| Teaching Assistant Stanford University | 1999–2002 |
| • Linear Dynamical Systems, Convex Optimization | |